GOVIND PATWAL

Phone: (647) 448-9325 | Email: <u>getintouchwithgovind@gmail.com</u> | Toronto, Canada LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/govindpatwal</u> | GitHub: https://github.com/Govind-Patwal

Portfolio: https://govind-patwal.github.io/

Python Programmer and Data Analyst with a certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization (Grade: A+) from the University of Toronto and years of experience in Sales and Project Management. Skills acquired from role as a Sales Executive include oral, written and presentation skills, ability to explain technical topics to non-technical audience, meeting deadlines, navigating competing priorities, and working under pressure in fast-paced environments. Skills acquired from a role as a Project Manager include scope, schedule, cost, quality, resource, risk, communication, stakeholder and risk management. Considers team work to be one of the biggest strengths - once worked with an external team to devise a win-win solution for the customer, own employer and the external team. Skilled in Python, Pandas, SQL, AWS, Tableau, Machine Learning and Deep Learning. Finds great satisfaction in extracting insights from data that inform decision-making and drive growth, and improving code by refactoring.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL

Applications: GitHub, PostgreSQL, GIT, AWS, Django, Flask, Tableau, SQLAlchemy

Tools: Pandas, NumPy, Jupyter Notebook, Scikit learn, TensorFlow

PROJECTS

European Hotel Analysis: https://github.com/Govind-Patwal/European Hotel Analysis

Project objectives - help users find the best hotel; second, help hotel owners know how customer sentiments are changing over time; and third determine the ML model that predicts the sentiments the best.

- Role: 1 of 3 contributors I was responsible for ETL, ERD, Schema and DB creation, ML and DL NLP models and creating a model to predict sentiment based on input.
- Language & Tools: Python, PostgreSQL, AWS, PySpark, Google Colab, Tableau

Movies ETL: https://github.com/Govind-Patwal/Movies ETL

Perform ETL (Extract-Transform-Load) on raw data from a scrape of wikipedia for all movies released since 1990, Kaggle metadata and rating data from MovieLens website.

• Role: Sole author

• Language & Tools: Python, SQL, SQLAlchemy

World Weather Analysis:

https://github.com/Govind-Patwal/World Weather Analysis To Create Travel Itinerary

The App is focused on travellers. Based on the preference of the temperature range of a user, it suggests hotels and the travel routes between the corresponding cities.

Role: Sole author

Language & Tools: Python, citipy, Weather Map API, gmaps API

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dell Technologies

Account Manager 2018 - Present

- Achieved an average target attainment of 120%.
- Attained top position on a campaign initiated by Mr. Kevin Connolly, President of Dell EMC Canada Commercial, in FY19Q4.

Adobe Systems

Account Manager 2016 - 2018

- Awarded with Sales Achievement Award by EVP, WW Field Operations.
- Recognized by BU Manager, for commitment to customers, and awarded with Top Customer Advocate Award.

Defacto Infotech

Sales Manager 2014 - 2016

- Increased new business by about 30%, response rate by about 20%, and conversion rate by about 10% by improving intra and inter team collaboration.
- Changed company's weakness to strength by starting a new model of working.
- Doubled as a Scrum-master in need.

Sebiz Infotech

Project Manager 2008 - 2014

- As a PMP, successfully managed over 200 SEO projects under a multitude of Scope, Time, Cost, and Resource constraints.
- Streamlined the SEO process in my team resulting in decreasing idle time and doubling productivity in strategic areas.
- Invented several new services to be offered to the clients my involvement was end-to-end.
- Built a SEO website from the scratch in HTML (designed, wrote content, and did SEO).

EDUCATION

University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada

Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization, Grade: A+

- A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning.
- Completed 19 Solo projects and 1 group project
- Scored 99.18% overall

Sikkim Manipal University, Chandigarh, India

Master of Business Administration, Information Systems

Indira Gandhi National Open University, New Delhi, India

Bachelor of Computer Applications